

# **JEONGHWAN LEE**



# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

5+ years of experience in human subject researches. Proven collaborator in inter- and multidisciplinary projects, led to 5+ peer-reviewed publications in engineering and clinical journals. Experience leading early lab and start-up company development, and mentoring professional growth of undergraduate students.

# **KEY SKILLS**

- Human Subject Research Experimental Design Biomechanical, Physiological Data Collection & Processing
- Human Motion Analysis
  Statistical Modeling
  Clustering & Classification
  Data Mining
  Design Optimization

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

**Programming** C/C++, Python, R, MATLAB

**Design Tools** Solidworks, CATIA, Solid Edge, EAGLE

**Engineering Tools** OpenSim, Simulink (real-time), Simscape, Labview, Multisim

Motion capture, EMG, IMUs, Pressure mats, Loadcells, Force plates, Indirect calorimetry **Experimental Tools** 

# **EDUCATION**

PhD in Mechanical Engineering, University of Texas at Austin, Austin, TX

**Expected Dec 2022** 

Area of Expertise: Post-stroke gait rehabilitation, Motion analysis, Locomotion biomechanics

MS in Mechanical Engineering, Seoul National University, Seoul, KR BS in Mechanical Engineering, Hanyang University, Seoul, KR

2017

2013

# RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

#### **Graduate Research Assistant**

Sept 2017 — Present University of Texas at Austin Austin, TX

# The effects of hip exoskeletal assistance on human locomotion

- · Analyze 10 post-stroke gaits with knee exoskeleton assistance and its simulated muscle mechanics by OpenSim to determine the predictor of a reflex response
- Examine biomechanical effects of exoskeleton's weight distributions by collecting & analyzing 20+ healthy individuals walking data with 10 different weight distribution mimicking hip exoskeleton

## Characterization of post-stroke stiff-knee gait

- Processed 50 post-stroke & 15 healthy individuals' treadmill walking data (e.g., kinematics, kinetics, EMG, GRF)
- Performed feature selection for 35+ gait parameters by applying a generalized linear mixed-effects Lasso regression
- Clustered post-stroke gait by using a multivariate time-series kernel k-means resulting in 3 different phenotypes

# Impact of kinematics and kinetics on classification of dual-task gait

- Developed experimental protocol for simulation study with 40 healthy participants, using cognitive-motor dual-task to test primary hypothesis
- · Implemented machine learning classification to differentiate between different gait conditions with above-chance performance

# Kinematic comparison of single degree-of-freedom robotic gait trainers

- Optimized designs of 1-DOF mechanisms (e.g., 4-, 6-, and 8-bar) to produce human-like end-effector motion trajectory
- · Evaluated optimal linkage configurations for motion trajectory accuracy by a comparison of 100+ healthy individuals gait

Research Assistant Mar 2017 — July 2017

Korea Institute of Science and Technology (KIST)

Seoul, KR

# Development of a surgical simulator for cranio-maxillofacial reconstructive surgery

 Researched a non-invasive, patient-specific surgical navigation method for an orbital reconstructive surgery, improving registration and tool tracking accuracy by up to 50%

#### **Graduate Research Assistant**

Sept 2013 — Aug 2014; Mar 2016 — Feb 2017

Seoul National University

Seoul, KR

# Needle steering scheme within limited DOFs for MR-guided breast needle intervention robot

• Devised a needle steering scheme with a pivoted super-elastic needle made of Nitinol for MR image-guided breast needle intervention robot, improving needle insertion angle and tip movement with zero actuator addition in robot

#### Prediction of human motion in vehicle ingress/egress using an artificial neural network

- Designed a low-cost (< \$1K) vehicle mock-up with four adjustable parameters for the research to predict human motion in ingress/egress movement
- Recruited & processed 10 healthy subjects of vehicle ingress/egress trials

Research Assistant Sept 2014 — Feb 2016

The University of Texas Health Science Center (UTHealth)

Houston, TX

# Development of a minimally invasive surgical robot with a continuum manipulator

- Designed a surgical grasper with an outer diameter of less than 3mm using an elastic element
- · Developed & prototyped a cable-driven continuum robotic manipulator for a minimally invasive single-port surgery

#### INTERNSHIPS

### **System Validation Engineer Intern**

May 2019 — Aug 2019

Harmonic Bionics, Inc.

Austin, TX

- · Devised hardware debugging & quality control frameworks for EtherCAT motion controller and sensor interface
- Documented a quality control & experimental log for a design iteration

#### **System Validation Engineer Intern**

May 2018 — Aug 2018

Harmonic Bionics, Inc.

Austin, TX

- Built a C/C++ source code library and tutorials for EtherCAT motion controller and sensor interface to allow users to create their own application solutions
- Designed demonstration kits (e.g., haptics interface) to exhibit at a tech conference

# **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

# **Graduate Teaching Assistant**

Feb 2018 — May 2021

University of Texas at Austin

Austin, TX

- Led 21-hours weekly mechatronics laboratory sections and instructed a circuit theory and hands-on circuit building
- Created and graded robot modeling, mechatronics assignments
- Mentored 10+ freshman students to develop a semester-long mechanical engineering research project

# SELECTED PUBLICATIONS (3 OF 7)

- [1] J. Lee, L. Li, S. Y. Shin, A. D. Deshpande, and J. Sulzer, "Kinematic comparison of single degree-of-freedom robotic gait trainers," *Mechanism and Machine Theory*, vol. 159, p. 104 258, 2021.
- [2] J. Lee, S. Y. Shin, G. Ghorpade, T. Akbas, and J. Sulzer, "Sensitivity comparison of inertial to optical motion capture during gait: Implications for tracking recovery," in 2019 IEEE 16th International Conference on Rehabilitation Robotics (ICORR), 2019, pp. 139–144.
- [3] J. Lee, K. Mekuria, T. G. Son, W. S. Jeong, J. W. Choi, and Y. Kim, "A novel noninvasive patient-specific navigation method for orbital reconstructive surgery: A phantom study using patient data," *Plastic and reconstructive surgery*, vol. 143, no. 3, 602e–612e, Mar. 2019.